So now that we understand what collision
resistant hash functions are and we know
现在我们理解了什么是抗碰撞的哈希函数
how to construct them, we're ready to
describe very popular MAC called HMAC. So
并知道了如何去建立它们 我们已经准备好去描述一种非常流行的MAC--HMAC了
let me remind you what the Merkle-Damgard construction is. Basically we have a
让我提醒你们一下什么是Merkle-Damgard机制
small compression function h from which we
build a large hash function, which is
我们有一个小的压缩函数h 根据这个函数h我们建立了一个大的哈希函数
collision resistant assuming the
compression function is collision resistant.
如果假设这个压缩函数具有抗碰撞性那么建立的大哈希函数也具有抗碰撞性
The question we're gonna ask
this segment is can we use the large hash
现在要考虑的问题是 我们能否用大的哈希函数去直接建立一个MAC
function to construct a MAC directly
without having to rely on a PRF. So here's
而不依赖于PRF呢
the first thing that comes to mind.
Suppose I give you a Merkle-Damgard hash
这是第一个首先想到的点 假设我给你一个Merkle-Damgard哈希函数
function so you notice a mapped, it hashes
large messages into small digests and we
你要注意到有一个映射 它把长信息通过哈希摘要变短
want to convert that directly into a Mac.
The first thing that comes to mind is well
而我们想把长信息直接转换为Mac 首先会想到的是既然这样
why don't we just hash the concatenation
of the MAC key as long with the message
为什么我们不直接对MAC密钥和消息的串接进行hash算法呢？
that we're trying to MAC? It turns out
that this is completely insecure so let me
因为这是极不安全的 那么问题来了
ask you, why is this is insecure?
为什么这样不安全
The answer is the standard extension of that, and if you think back to the
Merkle-Damgard construction, you realize
答案是由于它的标准扩散 如果你们能回想起来Merkle-Damgard机制
that if I tell you the tag of a particular
message, in other words I tell you the
你就会意识到如果我给你一个特定信息的标志 换言之我给你了这个点的值
value at this point. It's very easy for
the attacker to just add another block and
这样攻击者就很容易添加另一个分组
then compute one more application of the
compression function H. And now they'll be
然后再一次接受计算压缩函数H的请求
able to get the tag for the original
message concatenated the padding block,
现在他们也能够得到原始信息联结上补齐分组的标志了
concatenated the word W that they added
themselves and as a result this is an
而联结字W是他们自己加的 所以这是个存在伪造的可能性
existential forgery. Yes, so basically
this is exactly what we get here. Where
这个就是我们得到的
after concatenating the padding block, the
attacker can actually concatenate whatever
在联结补齐分组后 事实上攻击者可以任意联结他想要的
he wants and he would get the tag on this
combined message. So this is totally
然后他就会得到这个组合信息的标志
insecure and I cannot tell you how many
products have actually made this mistake
所以这是既不安全的 我无法告诉你们有多少产品犯过这种
where they assumed that this is a secure
Mac. This is completely insecure and
自认为这是个安全的Mac的错误
should never ever, ever, ever be used.
Instead there's a standardized method to
它是极不安全的 是永远不应该被采用的 然而有一种标准的方法
convert a collision resistant hash
function to a MAC and that method is
可以把一个抗碰撞的哈希函数转换成一个MAC 这个方法就是HMAC
called HMAC. So in particular we could use
the SHA-256 hash function to build
特别地 我们可以使用SHA-256哈希函数来建立这个MAC
this MAC. The output is going to be 256
bits and in fact HMAC is believed to be a
输出将是256位的 事实上HMAC被认为是一个伪随机函数
pseudo-random function, so in fact out of
SHA-256 we get a pseudo-random
所以通过SHA-256我们得到了一个输出为256位的伪随机函数
function that outputs 256 bit outputs. So
let me show the construction. Here's the
让我来展示一下这个机制
construction in symbols and it works as
follows. First we take our key k and we
这是用符号表示的机制 它的工作方式如下 首先我们取密钥k
concatenate what's we call an internal pad
to it, an ipad to it. This makes it into
然后我们在它后面联结一个叫做内部密码本的ipad
one block of the Merkle-Damguard
construction, so for example this would be
这使它成为了Merkle-Damguard机制的一个分组 举个例子
512 bits in the case of SHA256. We prepend
this to the message M and then we hash.
对于SHA-256而言将会是512位 我们把这个分组给信息M 然后求哈希
Now this by itself we just said is
completely insecure, however what HMAC
我们刚刚说过 只做这些是既不安全的 然而除此之外
does in addition, it takes the output,
which is 256 bits, it prepends to that the
HMAC还取了这256位输出 将密钥与外部密码本opad异或的结果附在这256位输出之前
key again XOR with, what's called the
outer pad, the opad. This also becomes
这也将使其变为512位的
512 bits. It's one block. And then it
hashes the combination of these two to
这是一个分组 然后它取这两个分组的哈希值
finally obtain the resulting tag on the
message M. So it's more rather looking
从而最终得到信息M的标志 相比与光看符号
into some symbols. It's more instructive
to look at HMAC in pictures. And so you
图像的方式更有利于对HMAC的直观理解
can see that here are the two keys k XOR
inner-pad, which is then fed into the
你可以看到这里有两个密钥k与内部密码本异或 然后交给Merkle-Damguard机制
Merkle-Damgard chain. And then the
resulting output of this chain is fed into
得到的输出再交给下一个Merkle-Damguard机制
another Merkle-Damgard chain and finally
the final output is produced. Okay, so
如此直至得到了最终的输出
this is how HMAC works in pictures and
now I want to argue that we've already
这就是HMAC的工作原理图示 现在我想证明一些我们已经见过的与此非常类似的东西
seen something very similar to this. In
particular, if you can think of the
特别的 如果你能想到
compression function H as a PRF where the
key is the first, the top inputs, then
以密钥为顶部输入 作为PRF的压缩函数H 那么我们
what we're actually doing here is we're
evaluating this PRF H at a fixed IV and
这里实际要做的是估算这个PRF H在确定IV
the result here is a random value which
we're gonna call K1. And then we apply the
这里的结果是随机值 我们称之为K1 然后我们应用
Merkle-Damgard chain and we can do the
same thing on the outer pad. If you think
Merkle-Damgard链对输出做同样的操作
of little h as a PRF where the key is the
upper inputs. Again, we're applying this
如果你认为以密钥为较高输入的h作为PRG 同样的 我们应用
PRF using a different key to a fixed value
IV and as a result, we're gonna get
这个PRF 使用一个不同的密钥到一个固定的值IV 我们会得到另一个随机值K2
another random value K2 So now when we
compute HMAC using these keys, K1 and K2,
现在 我们用这些密钥-K1,k2来计算HMAC
this would actually look very familiar
this is basically NMAC. It's identical to
这看起来会很熟悉 这就是HMAC 这和我们在之前
NMac that we discussed in a previous
segment. And notice to argue that this is
章节中讨论的NMAC相同 为了证明这是一个NMAC机制
an NMac construction we have to assume
that the compression function, little h,
我们必须假设压缩函数h是
is a PRF where the key is actually the
lower inputs to the function. Now let me
PRF并且密钥事实上是一个较低的输入
say that these pads, the ipad and the
opad , these are fixed constants that are
现在让我说说这些pad--opad和ipad 它们是固定的常数
specified in the HMAC standard. So these
are literally just 512 bit constants that
这是HMAC中特有的 就是固定不变的512比特
never change. And so when we go back to
look at the complete HMAC construction,
所以当我们回过头看完整的HMAC机制
you realize that the main difference
between this and NMAC is that these keys
你会意识到其和NMAC主要的区别是NAMC得到密钥是依据其他量的
here since they are dependent, you notice
they're both just the same key XORed
你注意到他们都是相同的密钥异或不同的常量
with different constants. Essentially, the
keys K1 and K2 are also somewhat dependent
本质上 密钥K1和K2也是一定意义上互相影响的
because they're computed by applying a PRF
to the same fixed value, namely IV, but
因为他们虽然是用PRF对同一个固定值（IV） 计算
with dependent keys. And so to argue that
K1 and K2 are pseudo random and
但用了相关联的密钥 那么讨论K1和K2是伪随机的并且
independent of one another, one has to
argue that the compression function not
不依赖于另一项 另一个必须说明的是压缩函数不仅是
only is a PRF where when the inputs, the
top input, is the key inputs, but it's
PRF作为输入 顶端输入是密钥输入 而且当使用相关联的密钥输入时
also a PRF when dependent keys are used.
But under those assumptions, basically the
它也是PRF 在这些前提下
exact same analysis NMAC would apply to
HMAC and we would get security argument
应用对NMAC完全相同的分析来分析HMAC 我们可以证明HMAC是一个安全的MAC
that HMAC is a secure MAC. So as I said,
HMAC can be proven secure under these PRF
HMAC是一个安全的MAC 所以如我所说 在这些
assumptions about the compression function
H. The security bounds are just as they
关于压缩函数H的PRF假设下HMAC可以被证明为安全的 其安全的界定
are for NMAC, in other words you should
not have to change the key as long as the
和NMAC相同 换句话说你不需要换密钥
number of messages you're MAC-ing Is
smaller than the size of the output tag to
只要你MAC信息的数量比输出标志小一半
the one-half, but for HMAC SHA256 the
output space is 2 to the 256. The square
但对HMAC SHA256 输出空间是2的256次方
root of that would put us at 2 to the
128. Which means that basically you can
平方根是2的128次方 也就意味着你能用HMAC SHA256
use HMAC SHA256 for as many outputs as you
want, and you'll always maintain security.
来得到足量你想要的输出并保证安全
And as a last point about HMAC I'll tell
you that TLS Standard actually requires
关于HMAC的最后一点我要告诉你的是 TLS标准事实上要求
that one support HMAC SHA-196 which means that
HMAC built form the SHA1 function and
必须支持HMAC SHA-196 也就是说从SHA1建立的HMAC函数截断到96比特
truncated to 96 bits. SHA-1 remember
outputs 160 bits. And we truncated to the
记住SHA-1输出160比特 然后我们得到最重要的96比特
most significant 96 bits. Now you might be
wondering, remember we said before that
现在你可能在想 记得我们之前所说的
SHA-1 is no longer considered a secure
hash function, so how come we're using
SHA-1不是我们以为的那么安全的哈希函数 那么我们
SHA-1 in HMac? Well, it turns out it's
actually fine. Because HMAC the analysis
为什么还在HMAC中用SHA-1 事实上这是可以的
of HMAC doesn't need SHA-1 to be
collision resistant. All it needs is that
因为HMAC的分析不需要SHA-1是阻止冲突的
the compression function of SHA-1
one be a PRF when either input is allowed
它需要的仅是SHA-1的压缩函数是PRF 并且输入可以是密钥
to be the key. And as far as we know
that's still correct for the underlying
就我们所知 对底层的SHA-1压缩函数这也是对的
compression function for SHA-1.
Even though it might not be collision
即使这样它可能不是阻止冲突的
resistant. As far as we know it's still
fine to use it inside of HMAC. So this is
就我们所知在HMAC内部使用它还是可行的
the end of our discussion of HMAC and in
our next segment we're going to look at
这就是我们对HMAC讨论的结果
timing attacks on HMAC.
下一节 我们将看HMAC的计时攻击